[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：我观察到的一个特别有用的抽象是
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: One abstraction that I've observed as particularly useful is to
从一个序列，一个事件序列的角度来思考事情。
think about things in terms of a sequence, a sequence of events.
我对序列的定义是，它是一个自动链接承诺的列表。
My definition for a sequence is that it's a list of automatically chained promises.
我们知道我们可以把承诺连在一起，我已经向你展示了如何做到这一点。
We know that we can chain promises together, I've shown you how to do that.
一旦你学会了它就很简单了。
It's pretty straightforward once you learn it.
五分钟，你和我们一样是这方面的专家。
Five minutes, you're an expert at it like the rest of us.
但是当你开始这样做的时候，几十个，几百个，
But as you start doing that, dozens and hundreds and
即使在一个项目中有数千次，
even thousands of times in a project,
你开始怀疑，天啊，我真的必须创造并返回另一个承诺吗？
you start to wonder gee, do I really have to create and return another promise?
它变得有点乏味，它变得非常乏味。
It gets a little bit tedious, it gets a lot tedious.
几年前，我是其中一些概念的早期采用者。
Years ago, I was an early adopter of some of these concepts.
在我们给它们起名字之前我就在做承诺了。
I was working on promises before we had a name for them.
就像五、六年前的prenode一样，我们正在研究如何将
Like five, six years ago, prenode, we were working on this concept of how to bring
这些东西和我是这方面的早期实验者。
this stuff and I was an early experimenter in this.
我认为最大的问题之一是，
And I decided that one of the big problems was,
我不想要记得去创造和
I don't want to have to remember to create and
承诺的链条当我的假设应该是，我总是会做另一步。
chain a promise when my assumption should be, I'm always gonna do another step.
为什么不让它自动为我创建和链接承诺。
Why not make it automatically create and chain promises for me.
所以我在五六年前做的早期实验，在我们有名字之前
So my early experiments into this five, six years ago, before we had a name for
承诺，早在您听说过的任何现有库之前
promises, long before any of the existing libraries that you've heard of were
我正在为这个抽象创建一个库。
around, is I was creating a library for that abstraction.
这个库经历了许多修订和几次名称更改。
And that library has gone through a lot of revisions and several name changes.
它最终得到了它现在使用的名称，即异步(Asynquence)
It eventually arrived at the name that it currently goes by, which is asynquence
这是单词asynch加上一起粉碎的单词序列，
which is the word asynch plus the word sequence smushed together,
主要是因为基本上没有其他好名字了[笑]。
mostly cuz there are no other good names left [LAUGH] basically.
必须想出一个独一无二的名字而没有其他好名字，
Gotta come up with a unique name and there were no other good names,
但它确实说明了它的目的。
but it does speak to what its purpose is.
其目的是向您呈现抽象，
Its purpose is to present you that abstraction,
一系列自动链接承诺的概念。
that notion of a sequence of a series of automatically chained promises.
你会注意到，我可以做一个链，就像你用承诺链做的那样，但是
You'll notice that I can do a chain just like when you do with a promise chain, but
这里有一些重要的区别。
there are some important differences here.
在第2行，您会注意到传递了我的Then函数
On line 2, you'll notice that my then function is passed
在我调用完成函数回调中，按照惯例，我称之为完成。
in function callback that I call done, just by convention, I call it done.
这就是我们的决议触发器。
That's our resolution trigger.
因此，无论何时第3行步骤完成，它都会调用Done，并
So whenever that step on line 3 is complete, it calls done and
这就是使序列进入下一步的原因。
that's what moves the sequence onto its next step.
承诺处理所有幕后创建的内容和
The promise to handle all that was created behind the scenes and
自动锁链这样我就不用担心那部分了。
automatically chained in so I didn't have to worry about that part.
我只需要担心什么时候发出信号，是时候继续前进了
I only needed to worry about when to signal that it was time to move on
到下一步。
to the next step.
所以他们的承诺绝对是在幕后发生的，但是
So their promises are absolutely happening under the covers but
它抽象了API的一些单调乏味的部分。
it's abstracting some of the tedious parts of that API.
它掩盖了一些粗糙的部分，
It's covering up some of the rough parts,
它正在以一种更明智的方式进行错误处理。
it's doing error handling in a more sensible way.
基本上，异步的设计是为了让承诺更容易推理，
Basically, the design of asynquence was to make promises easier to reason about,
更容易教。
easier to teach.
这是最初的设计目标。
That was the original design goal.
在这一点上，异步实际上远不止于此。
At this point, asynquence is actually quite a bit more than that.
它仍然具有相同的序列之类的概念，但是
It still has the same notion of a sequence and whatever, but
实际上，我并不是很经常使用异步的序列性质。
I actually don't really use the sequence nature of asynquence that much.
因为这些高阶模式也，我认为，更有趣，
Cuz these higher order patterns are also, I think, much more interesting,
我们将在研讨会结束前完成的事情。
the stuff that we're gonna get to through the end of the workshop.
但在其核心，制作序列所需的一切就是开始链接
But at its heart, all it takes to make a sequence is to start chaining
一步步走到一起就像你带着承诺和
steps together just like you would with a promise and
让它为你做一些工作。
letting it do some of that work for you.
所以第2行是a，那么，这只是一个常规步骤。
So line 2 is a .then, that's just a regular step.
但是第5行显示我可以创建一个gate step
But line 5 shows you that I can create a gate step
就像我可以做承诺一样。
just like I can do a promise.all.
但是不是有一个我返回承诺的函数。all from，
But rather than having a function that I return a promise.all from,
这是超级单调乏味的，我只是根据他们做什么来命名我的步骤。
which is super tedious, I just name my steps based upon what they do.
所以在这个API中，
So in this API,
它叫做.gate，如果你喜欢all to gate这个词，那么这里有一个.all的别名。
it's called .gate and there's an alias to .all if you prefer the word all to gate.
你可以使用任何你想要的，但它做的是完全相同的事情。
You can use whichever one you want, but it does exactly the same thing.
它接受这两个或多个函数，并行运行它们。
It takes those two or however many functions and runs them in parallel.
只要所有这些都成功完成，它就会继续前进。
Whenever all of them successfully complete, it moves on.
我不会试图说服或者
I am not going to try to convince or
向你推销你应该改用异步序列。
sell you that you should switch to using asynsequence.
然而，我设计了异步，使这些东西更容易教。
However, I designed asynquence to make this stuff easier to teach.
所以为了这个研讨会的平衡，
So for the balance of this workshop,
我们将要做的所有练习都将依赖于使用异步。
all the exercises that we're going to do are going to rely upon using asynquence.
所以你只需要学到足够的知识来完成这些练习
So you only have to learn it just enough to get through these exercises and
如果你再也不想用了，那完全没关系。
if you never want to use it again, that's totally fine.
但重要的是我们有一件事要学，而不是必须学
But it was important that we have one thing to learn rather than having to
学习15个不同的图书馆来做这件事。
learn 15 different libraries to do this stuff.
因此异步将处理我们将要讨论的所有内容
So asynquence will handle all the stuff that we will talk about
通过车间的其余部分。
through the rest of the workshop.
这就是为什么我给你一个简单的介绍它的工作方式。
It's why I'm giving you a brief introduction to the way that it works.
[咳嗽]&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：只是一个例子
[COUGH] &gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Just as an example
回到我们愚蠢的计算生命的意义。
back to our silly calculating the meaning of life.
这是Asynquence对生命意义的解释
Here's asynquence's version of meaning of life and
你会注意到在第8行，我使用了一个叫做瀑布的步骤。
you'll notice on line 8, I'm using a step called a waterfall.
这是我们可以定义的另一个高阶抽象。
That's another higher order abstraction that we could define.
瀑布仍然是一个连续的系列。
What a waterfall is is still a sequential series.
它不会做平行的事情，仍然是一个连续的系列，但是
It's not gonna do stuff in parallel, still a sequential series, but
它自动收集每个步骤的输出，并
it automatically collects the output from each step and
把它传给下一个和下一个。
passes it on to the next and the next and the next.
所以到最后，你就有了所有步骤的所有输出。
So by the end, you have all the outputs from all the steps.
你不必手动收集所有这些并将它们传递出去，
You don't have to manually collect all those and pass them along,
它会自动为你做到这一点。
it automatically does that for you.
所以在第12行的结尾，
So at the end on line 12,
我们从前面的两个系列步骤中获得了num1和num2。
we get both num1 and num2 from the two previous series steps.
这就是我所说的瀑布。
That's what I call a waterfall.
一些我经常做的事情
Something I was doing fairly often and
我非常手动地处理其他变量和
I was doing very manually with other variables and
我说让我们把它变成一个抽象，我们可以把它添加到库中。
I said let's make that into an abstraction that we can add into the library.
所以异步发货大约有10个或
So asynquence ships with about 10 or
15个核心方法是您需要的基本方法。
15 core methods that are the base ones that you need.
还有一个可选的contrib库，大约有15到20个其他库
And there's also an optional contrib library with about 15 to 20 other
可选的步骤方法，您可以为所有其他更高级别的东西添加这些方法。
optional step methods that you can add in for all this other higher level stuff.
我们将进入反应式编程和CSP
We'll get into reactive programming and CSP and
研讨会后面的其他事情。
other things later in the workshop.
另外需要指出的是，正如您在第12行所看到的，我有一个.seq step类型。
One other thing to point out, as you see on line 12, I have a .seq step type.
那是怎么回事？
What's that all about?
在常规的Promise库中，then函数是多态的。
Well in the regular Promise library, the then functions is polymorphic.
这是一种奇特的说法，它根据你返回的内容改变了它的行为，
That's a fancy way of saying it changes its behavior based upon what you return,
你用它做什么。
what you do with it.
我倾向于认为多态函数更容易混淆。
I tend to think that polymorphic functions are a bit more confusing.
所以当我查看then函数时，我实际上不知道它返回的是立即数
So when I look at a then function, I don't actually know is it returning an immediate
价值，是拒绝，是对某件事的承诺，
value, is it rejecting, is it returning a promise for something,
我不知道它在做什么，我必须更仔细地检查它。
I don't know what it's doing and I have to inspect it more closely.
异步的设计说，而不是只有一个多态函数
The design of asynquence said, rather than having one polymorphic function for
每件事，你命名步骤的基础上，步骤做什么。
everything, you name the step based upon what the step does.
所以序列步骤，
So the sequence step,
seq步骤期待返回序列，而序列类似于承诺。
the .seq step, is expecting a sequence back and a sequence is like a promise.
所以基本上是期待一个承诺，
So it's expecting a promise back basically,
这就是为什么我们回到第15行，就像你在正常的承诺中做的一样。
which is why we return on line 15 just like you do in a normal promise thing.
如果您确实需要在外部生成一个并返回它，请使用.seq步骤。
If you do need to produce one externally and return it, you use a .seq step.
如果您不需要自己生产，您可以使用.Then Step。
If you don't need to produce your own, you use a .then step.
如果你需要做一个同步的步骤，就像你只需要打印出一些东西，然后
If you need to do a synchronous step, like you just need to print something out and
您不需要执行任何异步操作，您可以使用.val作为值。
you don't need to do anything asynchronous, you use .val for the values.
检查或变换值。
You inspect or transform a value.
所以基本上，这个API的设计是这样的，每个方法名都是这样做的
So basically, the design of this API is such that each method name does
一件特定的事情，它的命名是基于这种期望，而不是
one specific thing, and its named based upon that expectation, rather than
必须学习一种方法的所有不同的多态行为。
having to learn all the different polymorphic behaviors of one method.